Guide to the Dumont de Bostaquet de Lamberville family papers M1366
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Dumont de Bostaquet de Lamberville family papers
circa 1600 - 1847
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Esclafer de la Rode, Patrick
Dumont de Bostaquet de Lamber
Dumont de Bostaquet family
M1366
2.5 Linear Feet (5 boxes)
Scope and Contents
Property documents, family titles and brief genealogies, correspondence, army documents, financial documents, property seizure under the revolution, restitution, etc. The 16th and 17th century documents nearly all relate to the Lesueur de Colleville and related families, and the 18th and 19th century documents to the five Isaac Dumonts and the two Samuel-Gabriel Dumonts.
For more information on this and two related collections in France, see Dianne W. Ressinger, "The Dumont de Bostaquet family in France and its archives, " Proceedings of the Huguenot Society of Great Britain and Ireland XXVIII:4 (2006):535-547.
Biographical / Historical
The collection comes from Isaac Antoine Auguste Dumont de Bostaquet, marquis de Lamberville, colonel d'Etat-major, decorated with the Ordre du Mérite militaire (the "Saint-Louis des protestants"), who died at Meudon en 1847. An émigré, he returned to Normandy to serve in the chouanne army of Frotté, who was his nephew, son of M. de Frotté, père, who married as his second wife Mlle Dumont de Bostaquet, the sister of the marquis de Lamberville. He lived in Rouen, and on his lands at La Fontelaye, Bostaquet, and Lamberville, and finally at the château de Beauregard, near Meudon. Although Huguenots, the Dumont de Bostaquet always remained faithful to the monarchy of the Bourbons [From dealer's description].
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research; material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased, 2003. Accession 2003-027.
France -- History.; Esclafer de la Rode, Patrick; Dumont de Bostaquet de Lamber; Dumont de Bostaquet family
- Deeds, 1600-1730 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Indemnity of Marquis de Colleville, émigré (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Family papers, correspondence, legal papers (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Farm at St Aubin de Cretot (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Legal papers (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Legal papers (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Legal and financial papers (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Legal papers, M. Dumont de Bostaquet (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Financial papers (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Financial papers (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Legal and financial papers concerning Beauregard (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Legal and financial papers (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Legal and financial papers (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Financial papers (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Correspondence and financial papers (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Financial papers (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Correspondence; financial papers (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Documents concerning the mills at Bourdainville and Baulot (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Constitution viagère by M. Dumont de Lamberville (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Papers concerning Adrien Boulen (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Correspondence and accounts with M. Hardy, notary at Rouen (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Financial papers (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Mill at Beautot; financial affairs with Mme LeGendre (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Financial affairs with the heirs Duforestie; Lafoutelaye (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Letters from Fauvel; 3 accounts with Lenormand; 1 letter from M. Duquesnoy, 1840-1843 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Farms at Avresmenil and Longueil; land at Varvannes (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Quit-claim from M. Lelennier, 1829 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Report on the mill at Delaunay, 1814 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Bornage between M. de Lamberville, Mme. Leprevost, M. de St. Victor & Mme. Duquesnoy (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Quit-claim from M. de bostaquet to Melle. de Romé (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Inscriptions hypothècaires contre M. de Lamberville (Box 4, Folder 9)
- La masse Charenton; revocation of procurations (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Guérillon trial concerning the passage of the herd, 1714 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- The farm of Jean d'Aptot (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Debts from M. de Lamberville to the Massa sisters, 1837 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Cession & constitution from M. Thézard to M. Dumont de Lamberville; transfert of income (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Financial papers (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Affairs with the Caudebec family (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Financial affairs (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Emigré affairs (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Affairs with the de Dieppe family (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Indemnity of M. de Lamberville (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Financial affairs (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Financial affairs (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Financial affairs (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Financial affairs (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Emigré affairs (Box 5, Folder 11)